Guide to the Charles Benton Power papers 1870-1971
Montana Historical Society Research Center
- Charles B. Power Estate (co-administrators Blanche Mares and C.M. Wall)
  - Court Papers
    - Petitions for probate of will (includes copy of will), November 1953 (Box-folder 12 / 14)
    - First accounting, 1959 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
    - Final accounting and decree closing Estate, 1960 (Box-folder 12 / 16)
  - Financial Records
    - Receipts and disbursements, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 12 / 17)
    - Sums advanced to Pauline Eby Power, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 12 / 18)
    - Tax returns and working papers, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 13 / 1-2)
    - Trial balances, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 13 / 3)
    - U.S. Treasury bills, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 13 / 4)
    - C.M. Wall fees, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
  - Legal Documents
    - Quit claim deed, mortgage, 1956, 1957 (Box-folder 13 / 6)
  - Subject Files
    - Bismarck, N.D., real estate (includes some C.B. Power letters, 1944-1947), 1944-1959 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
    - Cascade Milling and Elevator Company, 1943-1954 (Box-folder 13 / 8)
    - Insurance, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 13 / 9)
    - Inventories, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 13 / 10)
    - Rev. Leo T. Martin claim, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 13 / 11)
    - Mining: Brownstone Quarry, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 13 / 12)
    - Mining: Bullion and Pine Tree lodes, 1940-1969 (Box-folder 13 / 13)
    - Mining: Ming's Bar, 1889-1971 (Box-folder 13 / 14-15)
    - Mining: O'Connor, Sadie, and Susie lodes, 1907-1963 (Box-folder 13 / 16)
    - Mining: Surprise Mining Claim (includes correspondence, history by Carl J. Trauerman), 1901-1967 (Box-folder 13 / 17-18)
    - Mining: Surprise Mining Claim (includes legal documents; maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3), 1901-1931 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
    - Mining: Yellowstone Mining Company (Castle Mining District), 1893, 1939-1959 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
    - Montana Opera House, 1955 (Box-folder 14 / 3)
    - Powhold Company, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 14 / 4)
    - Real estate: Helena (re Getchell and Childs placer claim, lot E), 1916-1957 (Box-folder 14 / 5)
    - Real estate: Helena (re Gold Block, Power Block, Diamond Block; includes prospective buyers), 1954-1957 (Box-folder 14 / 6)
    - Real estate: Manhattan, Mont., 1954-1972 (Box-folder 14 / 7)
    - Rock Creek Ranch Company, 1947-1958 (Box-folder 14 / 8)
    - Safety deposit box, 1954, 1959 (Box-folder 14 / 9)
    - Toole County land (includes correspondence, escrow agreement, oil and minerals, abstracts of title, taxes, legal documents), 1926-1962 (Box-folder 14 / 10-16)
    - T.C. Power Company, 1954 (Box-folder 14 / 17)
    - T.C. Power and Brother, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14 / 18)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of corporate reports filed and expiration of corporate charters (lists all C.B. Power companies), 1927, 1943 (Box-folder 14 / 19)
    - Notes by Blanche Mares re management of C.B. Power's affairs, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 14 / 20)
  - Clippings
    - Re death of C.B. Power, Estate, friends, etc., 1953-1958 (Box-folder 14 / 21)
- Mabel Larson Power (Mrs. C.B. Power)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - American Poets' Ambulances in Italy (re memorial for poet Alan Seeger), 1917 (Box-folder 15 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank statements, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 15 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Address book, undated (Box-folder 15 / 3)
- Benton Power (Charles Benton Power, Jr.)
  - School Notes and Records
    - Hawthorne School, Mount St. Charles College high school dept. report cards, etc., 1917-1925 (Box-folder 15 / 4)
    - Georgetown University report cards, graduation, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 15 / 5)
  - Miscellany
    - S.S. Belgenland world cruise photograph list, 1931 (Box-folder 15 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (includes speech on World War I, Society of Sons and Daughters of Montana Pioneers membership), 1917, 1926 (Box-folder 15 / 7)
- Jane Power Tobin
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Branson G. Stevenson (re etching entitled "Springhill, Helena"), undated (Box-folder 15 / 8)
  - School Notes and Records
    - St. Helena Parochial School, St. Vincent's Academy, H.H. Hirschfeld piano lessons, 1919-1929 (Box-folder 15 / 9)
    - Dominican College, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 15 / 10)
    - College Montmorency, France, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 15 / 11)
  - Miscellany
    - Miscellaneous (includes letter of introduction from her pet dog, Society of Sons and Daughters of Montana Pioneers membership, Thomas Tobin certificate), 1925, 1926, 1952 (Box-folder 15 / 12)
- Margaret Power Drum Carrick
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Mary G. Power, Charles B. Power), 1916-1925 (Box-folder 15 / 13)
  - School Notes and Records
    - Notebook, report cards, 1915, 1921 (Box-folder 15 / 14)
  - Miscellany
    - Cruise, 1924 (Box-folder 15 / 15)
    - Wedding to Frank Goss Drum, 1924 (Box-folder 15 / 16)
  - Clippings
    - Society items, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 15 / 17)
- Flanagan Family
  - Financial Records
    - Taxes: Dubuque, Iowa, 1842-1872 (Box-folder 15 / 18)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes marriage certificate of Mathew Flanagan and Mariam McNamara, Margaret Carmady vs. Mathew Flanagan, estate papers of Mathew Flanagan, agreements), 1836-1866 (Box-folder 15 / 19)
- T.C. Power and Brother
  - Financial Records
    - Ledger (includes many of the Power companies), 1921-1935 (Box-folder 16 / 1)
    - Memo books (include many of the Power companies), 1902-1915 (Box-folder 16 / 2-3)
    - Sale of cattle, 1919 (Box-folder 16 / 4)
    - Miscellaneous (re sale of furs, robes, general merchandise, etc.), 1870s (Box-folder 16 / 5)
    - Miscellaneous (removed from minute book), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 16 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract with Parlin and Orendorff Plow Company, 1914 (Box-folder 16 / 7)
  - Organization
    - Bylaws, 1917 (Box-folder 16 / 8)
    - Minute book, 1917-1940 (Box-folder 16 / 9)
    - Minute book, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 17 / 1)
    - Minutes (draft, different from final), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 17 / 2)
    - Stock certificates, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 17 / 3)
- T.C. Power and Brother [fictitious company for C.B. Power]
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1944-1953 (Box-folder 17 / 4)
    - Ledger, 1944-1953 (Box-folder 17 / 5)
    - Trial balances, 1949, 1951 (Box-folder 17 / 6)
- T.C. Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Ledger, 1914-1931 (Box-folder 18 / 1)
    - Montana Oil Company price quotes, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 18 / 2)
  - Organization
    - Minute book, 1896-1931 (Box-folder 18 / 3)
    - Miscellaneous (removed from minute book), 1896-1931 (Box-folder 18 / 4)
  - Subject Files
    - Contract with Peter Schuttler Company (to sell their wagons; includes contract, correspondence, financial records), 1916-1917 (Box-folder 18 / 5)
    - Contract with U.S. Army Quartermaster's Office (to supply oats for the army in the Philippines; includes contract, correspondence, financial records), 1912-1913 (Box-folder 18 / 6)
    - Hay contracts (includes contract, correspondence, financial records), 1916 (Box-folder 18 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Radio spot advertisements re history of Fort Benton, 1931 (Box-folder 18 / 8)
- Benton Group of Mines
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (includes Walter M. Leuthold, Gwen Vaughan-Rhys, American Metal Climax, Inc.), 1959, undated (Box-folder 19 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balances, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 19 / 2)
- Benton Hardware Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - T.C. Power and Brother to J.B. Rauch (re affairs of Benton Hardware Company), 1924 (Box-folder 19 / 3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deed and bill of sale, 1917 (Box-folder 19 / 4)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation, bylaws, etc. (some removed from minute book), 1899-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 5)
    - Minute books, 1899-1936 (Box-folder 19 / 6-7)
    - Stock certificates, 1899-1927 (Box-folder 19 / 8)
- Benton Transportation Company
  - Miscellany
    - List of steamboats compiled by I.P. Baker, 1923 (Box-folder 19 / 9)
    - Steamboat logs: Benton, 1881; Mandan, 1905, 1881, 1905 (Box-folder 19 / 10)
- Big Sag Land and Livestock Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Wallace Kingsbury and James Butler to J.W. Chivers, 1918-1925 (Box-folder 19 / 11)
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1917-1925 (Box-folder 19 / 12)
    - Ledger, 1917-1925 (Box-folder 19 / 13)
  - Organization
    - Stockholder journal, 1893-1925 (Box-folder 20 / 1)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1896-1919 (Box-folder 20 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of land, etc., 1912-1932 (Box-folder 20 / 3)
- Faith Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Montana School of Mines, Thomas D. Tobin, Blanche Mares, T.J. Vaughan-Rhys, Gwen Vaughan-Rhys McBride, Elon Davis, Montana State Forester, John H. Risken, Montana State Board of Health re pollution of Belt Creek, Montana Bureau of Mines and Geology, H.J. Anderson, 1946-1970 (Box-folder 21 / 1-2)
  - Financial Records
    - Assay certificates and ore settlements, 1900-1964 (Box-folder 21 / 3)
    - Insurance policies on compressor, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 21 / 4)
    - Journals, 1930-1953, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 5-6)
    - Ledgers, 1930-1953, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 7-8)
    - Montana Industrial Accident Board/Workmen's Compensation Division insurance, 1951-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 9)
    - Montana Unemployment Compensation Commission payroll reports, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 21 / 10)
    - Taxes, 1953-1977 (Box-folder 21 / 11)
    - Trial balances, 1934-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 12)
    - Miscellaneous (includes financial statements, invoices, etc.), 1930-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes leases, management contracts, quit claim deeds, etc.), 1967-1977 (Box-folder 21 / 14)
  - Organization
    - Annual reports of corporation, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 21 / 15)
    - Liquidation of company, 1974 (Box-folder 21 / 16)
    - Minute book (includes bylaws), 1925-1958 (Box-folder 22 / 1)
    - Minutes [loose, incomplete], 1963-1968 (Box-folder 22 / 2)
    - Stockholder lists, 1927-1958 (Box-folder 22 / 3)
  - Reports
    - Report on Faith Mining Company, by Mason W. Rankin (includes related correspondence, and map of workings; claim maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1954 (Box-folder 22 / 4)
  - Subject Files
    - Amex Exploration, Inc., 1973-1980 (Box-folder 22 / 5)
    - Annual assessment work (includes interoffice correspondence about operation of mine, etc.), 1950-1978 (Box-folder 22 / 6-7)
    - Lease operation by Harry J. Anderson and Peter Antonioli, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 22 / 8)
    - Lease operation by Gwen Vaughan-Rhys McBride, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 22 / 9)
    - Lease operation by Roy and Alfred R. Thorson, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 22 / 10)
    - Pollution of Belt Creek by Block P Mine, 1925, undated (Box-folder 22 / 11)
    - Prospective buyers: American Smelting and Refining Company, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 22 / 12)
    - Prospective buyers: miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 22 / 13)
    - Unpatented claims: reports to U.S. Forest Service, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 22 / 14)
  - Miscellany
    - List of mining claims, 1967 (Box-folder 22 / 15)
  - Clippings
    - Great Falls Tribune article re Monarch, 1960 (Box-folder 22 / 16)
- Helena Building and Realty Company / Power Block
  - Court Papers
    - Alice E. Feldman vs. Helena Building and Realty Company (injury suit), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 23 / 1)
    - Minnie Tannant vs. Helena Building and Realty Company (re death of her daughter Helen June Tannant, 13-year-old elevator operator), 1943-1952 (Box-folder 23 / 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Audit reports, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 23 / 3)
    - Cash books, 1920-1931 (Box-folder 23 / 4-7)
    - Gold block and V Building bonds, 1900 (Box-folder 23 / 8)
    - Insurance policies, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 23 / 9)
    - Journal, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 24 / 1)
    - Miscellaneous (includes tax receipts, bond coupons, rent lists, trial balance sheet), 1916-1971 (Box-folder 24 / 2-3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Mortgage papers, 1938, 1955 (Box-folder 24 / 4)
    - Sale of properties to Thomas D. Tobin [he operated them as Power Block], 1955-1958 (Box-folder 24 / 5)
    - Title examination, 1938 (Box-folder 24 / 6)
  - Organization
    - Dissolution of company, 1957 (Box-folder 24 / 7)
    - Minutes, 1942, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 24 / 8)
  - Subject Files
    - Diamond Block, 1923-1966 (Box-folder 24 / 9-10)
    - Insurance (includes fires), 1938-1956 (Box-folder 24 / 11)
    - Tenants: Army-Navy Stores, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 24 / 12)
    - Tenants: Hugo Dobler Adjusters, 1933-1972 (Box-folder 24 / 13)
    - Tenants: Helena Office Supply, 1933-1969 (Box-folder 24 / 14)
    - Tenants: Dorothy Osborne, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 24 / 15)
    - Tenants: John Risken, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 24 / 16)
- Phoenix Development Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Blanche Mares, Union Bank and Trust Company, Holter Realty Company, Lester H. Loble, Thomas Topping, Lucile Topping, Polar Refrigeration), 1952-1956 (Box-folder 25 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Insurance (re buildings at Main and Lawrence Streets, includes fire of 1950), 1927-1957 (Box-folder 25 / 2-3)
    - Trial balances and audits, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 25 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes mortgage, options, etc.), 1951-1955 (Box-folder 25 / 5)
- Unit Petroleum Company [non-incorporated]
  - Organization
    - Stock certificate books, 1920 (Box-folder 25 / 6-7)
- Transfers to other programs
  - Transfers
    - List of artifacts transferred to Museum (Box-folder 25 / 8)